# RAJAT SRIVASTAVA

#### **SUMMARY**

Highly effective software developer offering a wealth of more than 3+ years of relevant expertise. A valuable team player who also is personable and dedicated. Seeking the chance to bring further success to an established organisation through development, testing, and software debugging.

#### CONTACT

**☑** rajatsri94@gmail.com

**in** rajatsriv19

**\** 9910364830

najat19

**♀** Delhi

# **EDUCATION**

# Ajay Kumar Garg Engineering College, Ghaziabad BTech Computer Science 2017

Graduated with 80.68%

Member of Open Source R&D Team Organized Tech Events in College

#### **SKILLS**

BACKEND DEVELOPMENT: Node js(Koa/Express), Django,

Java Spring

**DATABASE:** Mysql, Sqlite, Mongo DB **PROGRAMMING:** C, C++, Java, Python

OTHER SOFTWARES/TOOLS: Git, Redis Cache, Jenkins,

Apache Storm, Kafka, RabbitMQ

### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

#### **Jsniper**

Node cli based project that creates new projects based on already provided templates. Hosted on npm and github packages

#### Keep In Touch

Application that reminds its customers to keep in touch with their dear ones. Reminders can be scheduled as per convenience.

#### **Torrent Crawler**

Command line interface to fetch torrents and subtitles for a movie. Hosted on pypi

#### Hackerrank Crawler

Crawl Hackerrank Solutions using command line. Hosted on pypi

#### Kora

Book sharing web app using Python and Django. Hosted on heroku

#### Geosearch

A geographical based search engine build upon Laravel Framework

#### Timetable Management System

Timetable management for college using Machine Learning Options to mark attendance for faculties

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Paytm

Noida

Software Engineer · Sept. 2018

- Working on Paytm Green Gaming System
- Designed and Developed Paytm's Scratch Card System
- Developed Paytm's lucky draw feature
- Worked on integration of Payment Bank's pipeline with Paytm reward system
- Developed realtime gratification and multiple gratification for Paytm's post transaction reward system
- Worked on localisation of apis for Paytm Cashback System

## Smartprix Web

Noida

Software Developer · June 2017 to Aug. 2018

- Designed Node JS and Vue JS based admin web applications.
- Developed Smartprix new website using Node JS and Marko JS
- Developed Smartrank, an online IDE for test purposes
- Worked on Smartprix Crawler to extract data from appropriate websites
- Worked on Smartprix tiny url service smpx.to

# Sysbiome Technologies

Noida

Intern · June 2016 to July 2016

- Developed Samarpan project for recruitment purpose using Laravel
- Wrote all technical documentation for new software
- Developed native Android mobile applications for Samarpan.

#### Justwravel

Noida

Intern · Sept. 2015 to Nov. 2015

- Worked on JustWravel.com using CodeIgniter framework
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications

# Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam Technical University

Web Developer (Contractual) · Sept. 2015 to Nov. 2015

- Designed Question Paper Portal
- Received letter of appreciation from university

#### Nisani India

Noida

Intern · May 2015 to Sept. 2015

- Applied knowledge of JavaScript and Object-Oriented Programming to create successful designs-
- Built Student ERP Portal website interface with HTML and CSS

# **AWARDS**

Paytm · Rockstar Sept. 2020

Paytm · Rockstar Oct. 2019